<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 12:05:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Preset Layouts in I3</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-preset-layouts-in-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 12:05:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-preset-layouts-in-i3/</guid>
      <description>While I already knew how to launch programs with my i3 config file, I was lacking a way to predefine specific workspace layouts that I would want to launch on startup.
That’s where i3 layouts come in handy.
The first step in creating a layout is to spawn the windows you want to be launched when the layout is deployed.
In this example I created a monitor layout, which I use to monitor system stats, crypto prices, the news, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Productivity Todo App</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/super-productivity-todo-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:21:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/super-productivity-todo-app/</guid>
      <description>Brief: Super Productivity is an awesome open-source to-do app that helps you manage tasks, track tickets, and manage time.
No matter what you do, improving productivity is a common goal for most of the people. Usually, you would end up trying various to-do list apps or a note-taking app to help yourself organize and remind things to efficiently keep up with your work.
Sure, you can check out those lists and try them as you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Min Browser Almost Good Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/min-browser-almost-good-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 19:42:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/min-browser-almost-good-enough/</guid>
      <description>Min Browser: Almost good enough The Min Browser is a minimalist web browser designed for productivity. In this review, I, Cukmekerb, will try it and tell you what I think.
First thoughts Min is not in the AUR (there&amp;rsquo;s a beta version that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated since 2018), but it it is available to download as a .deb or .rpm. Since I&amp;rsquo;m running Manjaro, which is not based on Debian, I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Debtap to install it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:17:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Brief: This tutorial shows you how to install Arch Linux in easy to follow steps.
Arch Linux is a general-purpose rolling release Linux distribution which is very popular among the DIY enthusiasts and hardcore Linux users.
The default installation covers only a minimal base system and expects the end user to configure the system by himself/herself.
This is why installing Arch Linux is a challenge in itself but at the same time, it is a learning opportunity for intermediate Linux users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Markdown in Vim</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-markdown-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 09:05:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-markdown-in-vim/</guid>
      <description>If you are working with something that works like CommonMark and does not insert a &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; for every newline character then you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to display trailing spaces, so that you know when you actually have the two trailing spaces needed to insert a &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;. See Showing Invisible Things In Vim for how to do this.
Troubleshooting In the course of writing this I encountered a number of problems.
Terminal Vim displayed a background color for italic text and bold text was bolded, but in my Gui Vim they both just looked like all the other text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orion Twitch Client for Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/orion-twitch-client-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:57:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/orion-twitch-client-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>Orion- Twitch Client For Linux Orion is a free and open source QML / C++ client for Twitch.tv which can use multiple player backends (including mpv). The application runs on Linux, Windows, macOS and Android. Using Orion you can watch live Twitch streams and past broadcasts, and browse or search games and channels using a nice material user interface. What&amp;rsquo;s more, Orion lets you login to Twitch, so you can chat and follow channels (and receive notifications when a channel you follow goes online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Still Use Vim</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-i-still-use-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:37:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-i-still-use-vim/</guid>
      <description>Why I Still Use Vim And no, it’s not because I can’t figure out how to close it.
Image: http://amzn.to/2umsBaY
I often get asked about why I use Vim as my primary editor, there is no particular reason for this, except that I ended up learning it when I moved over to Linux full time many years ago. I ended up liking it because I could edit my small source files on my quad-core machine without needing to wait forever for the file to open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Galliumos on Chromebook</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/how-to-install-galliumos-on-chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 23:12:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/how-to-install-galliumos-on-chromebook/</guid>
      <description>— May 24, 2020
This is a repost of a guide I made on a different blogging platform when I only owned an ex-chromebook. It talks about how to install unlocked BIOS and install GalliumOS (a linux distro using xfce to make a chromeOS - like linux experience.)) Note: to do this, all your chromeOS data will be wiped. I recommend reading through all of this post before starting.
This post is about how I got my chromebook dual booting galliumOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Essential Vim Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-essential-vim-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 16:25:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-essential-vim-plugins/</guid>
      <description>10 essential Vim plugins Vim remains a powerful and ubiquitous application to tackle any number of text editing tasks conveniently from the terminal (some learning required). If you’re looking to add Vim to your toolkit this year, here is my list of absolutely essential plugins to begin supercharging your workflow.
If you’ve never set up a Vim plugin before, see the Installing Vim plugins section later on for a runthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Reasons Why Linux Is Better</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/12-reasons-why-linux-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 21:44:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/12-reasons-why-linux-is-better/</guid>
      <description>12 reasons why Linux is better than Windows The myth that Linux is complex and only needed by programmers and developers is not true.
Windows is the most popular operating system, and it is well deserved. She has come a long way, constantly improving and developing. However, although Microsoft claims that the Ten is its best creation, in some things Linux is far superior to Windows.
1. Convenient implementation of updates Perhaps we all know about this situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Ricing and How I Do It (just the basics)</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-ricing-and-how-i-do-it-just-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 13:15:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-ricing-and-how-i-do-it-just-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>Everyone is always asking me, how do I rice linux so fast? And The answer is, I just have the some bash scripts set to keybinds. For the i3 window manager.
Script 1: Pywal So for this one you need pywal.
wal -i $HOME/Pictures/wallpapers -o wal-set Script 2: Sublime text theme This is a python script
#! /usr/bin/env python import json import os def make_element(name, scope, **kwargs): &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;Helper function for generating color scheme entries&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; result = {} result[&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;] = name result[&amp;#39;scope&amp;#39;] = scope result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life So Far</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/my-life-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/my-life-so-far/</guid>
      <description>My Life So Far So, I had an idea to just write about my life today, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m gonna do. Enjoy!
Projects I am working on  Opensuspect (more on this later) AlamodeBoot My website  Things I have done  CFWed my 3ds installed i3 and made it look cool got 1.4k upvotes on reddit  Things I want to do  Install Arch Linux Format my stupid corrupted SD card make more storage on my laptop  Opensuspect So, OpenSuspect is an open-source social deduction game, similar to among us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with i3wm</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/getting-started-with-i3wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/getting-started-with-i3wm/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with i3wm My friends always get surprised when I show them how do I use i3. Unfortunately, the problem of using i3 is probably the same as in vi. You won’t be able to use alt+tab and everything is command-based, so by the end of the day, restart your computer to select an GUI will be easier, but I hope that after a few days (or maybe weeks) using it, you won’t want to use anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Linux User&#39;s Thoughts on Macos</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/a-linux-users-thoughts-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 23:44:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/a-linux-users-thoughts-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>A MacBook Pro isn&amp;rsquo;t a professional machine, and macOS isn&amp;rsquo;t impressive As a full-time Linux user, I have never cared much about Apple products. All of my previous computers were PCs that came with Microsoft Windows, which I invariably removed before putting Linux on it. Apple products are overpriced, and installing Linux on MacBooks is, in general, trickier than on an average PC, so I have looked away from MacBooks for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Ricing Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-ricing-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 17:43:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-ricing-basics/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Here are my dotfiles.
Disclaimer: I am in no way a ricing expert. This guide is intended for fellow beginners confused on the very basics when it comes to the customization of their Unix system.
Introduction After making my departure to Arch Linux a month ago I was quickly introduced to the world of tiling window managers. The idea is that instead of having a full blown desktop environment (DE) such as Gnome or Unity, you just have a window manager that utilizes keyboard shortcuts to organize your windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Snaps in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 11:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Intro Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, snaps are great in theory - If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar, a snap package is like a sandboxed application that is packaged in such a way that:
 You can be sure you&amp;rsquo;re running exactly what the app developer intended, as all dependencies and assets are bundled into the snap application package The snap application generally doesn&amp;rsquo;t own your entire system, it runs in an application sandbox of sorts Snaps are cross-platform and distributed independently from apt/deb packages, and as such are usually more up to date than those found in apt  Now this all sounds great, and it is in some ways (especially for app developers), but it comes at a cost: and that is generally performance and annoyances with application theming, access to user folders, and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Learn Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-you-should-learn-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:50:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-you-should-learn-linux/</guid>
      <description>Why You Should Probably Learn Linux Let’s face it, Linux sounds scary to the untrained ear. Most average users think of black and white terminals, and pale, white, basement dwellers clacking assembly and basic into an ancient IBM machine when they hear the term “ Linux” arise in conversation. Of course, the same might not be said for Data Scientists, and programmers alike, but the stigma is certainly still illustrated inside of that particular clique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:05:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know From switching your private keys to directory listings with hidden files
As a developer, there are two key things that are paramount to a productive setup: speed and efficiency.
The more time you take to accomplish simple tasks like searching for files or displaying their contents, the more is taken from critical development time. When working on the command-line, things like aliases and custom functions can speed things up and let you get back to developing more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Linux Software</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/best-linux-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:02:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/best-linux-software/</guid>
      <description>Best Linux Desktop Software Awards per Category for 2017! hey! you do realize that this post is only written because i was bored to do anything else, right?
also i want to make super clear that on these awards, we ran a set of completely democratic procedures, with a fully transparent voting. and by “we” i mean “me”, and by “voting” i mean a single vote! “mine” 👐
i will try to cover some basic categories, but not everything!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Survival Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-survival-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 13:02:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-survival-guide/</guid>
      <description>Linux: A Survival Guide for Beginners I survived the transition to Linux—and you can too
Photo by Chris Ried on Unsplash
Switching from Windows to Linux can be really scary. But if you can survive the first few months, the eventual returns are exponential. Here’s how I survived.
TLDR   Though I am just an amateur in Linux, I was able to survive the transition and indeed benefitted from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ventoy Persistence</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/ventoy-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/ventoy-persistence/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I have discussed how to create multiboot USB drives with Ventoy application. Today, I will see how to create persistent bootable USB using Ventoy in Linux. As you may already know, a regular bootable medium allows us to test the Linux distributions without having to install them on the hard drive. When you are on a Live OS, you can do all sort of things, such as installing applications, downloading files, playing media, creating files and folders, customizing it as per your liking and a lot more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ventoy Multiboot USB</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/ventoy-multiboot-usb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/ventoy-multiboot-usb/</guid>
      <description>Ventoy is a free, open source and cross-platform program to create multiboot USB drives in Linux and MS Windows. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to format your USB devices over and over. Just create a bootable USB drive once and add as many as ISOs you want in future. Ventoy will automatically create the menu entries for the newly added ISOs and add them to the boot menu. Once you created the multiboot USB, boot your system with the USB drive, select the ISO you want to load and start using it in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Site</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/my-new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/my-new-site/</guid>
      <description>My new site Introduction Remember my old site, with my orange theme and ugly font? Well, that is no more!! I have created a new site with a site generator called hugo. Hugo is like jekyll, but more customizable.
Why? Why did I choose to use hugo, over anything else? The first reason is that it is more customizable. The options are not limited to github pages rules. My second reason is that it has lots of themes, like this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Linux Commands</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/important-linux-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/important-linux-commands/</guid>
      <description>Important Linux Commands: Linux Commands You Must Know In 1991 when Linus Torvalds for the first time publicly shared his newly made kernel completely free from minix code, then even he was not aware of its capabilities in bringing the revolution in the software industry at that time. The open source we hear today was not much popular back then, not until linux was founded. You see, Git a very popular VCS(Version Control System) was founded by the same guy to maintain the linux kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>After witnessing insane minimalism paired with a tiler (tiling window manager), knew it was my time to take the pilgrimage to Arch Linux. Some characteristics that make Arch unique:
 The Arch Way embody the principles behind Arch Linux; simplicity, modernity, pragmatism, user centrality and versatility. Forces one to build the system up by hand. This encourages you to question the role of each component of the system, and available options to satisfy that component (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Linux is Better</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-linux-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-linux-is-better/</guid>
      <description>10 Reasons Why Linux Is Better Than Windows It is often seen that people get confused over choosing Windows or Linux as a host operating system in both server and desktop spaces. People will focus on aspects of cost, the functionality provided, hardware compatibility, support, reliability, security, pre-built software, cloud-readiness, etc. before they finalize. In this regard, this article covers ten reasons for using Linux over Windows.
10 Reasons Why Linux Is Better Than Windows 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Gaming Distros</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/best-gaming-distros/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/best-gaming-distros/</guid>
      <description>Best Linux Distros for Gaming There are so many Linux distributions for gamers you would find today. If you’re confused with all the options you could choose from, we got you covered.
We’ve compiled a list to help you pick the best Linux distro for your gaming preference and needs.
1. Steam OS Let’s start the list off with Steam OS. This is one of the most popular gaming distros today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual Boot Linux Mint</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/dual-boot-linux-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/dual-boot-linux-mint/</guid>
      <description>Dual Boot Linux Mint 20 and Windows 10 With recent rapid increases in information technology, every user wants to customize their operating system environment according to their needs. Today, we will talk about the most popular Linux Mint 20 distribution, known as Ulyana. Linux Mint is an open-source, flexible, community-based Linux operating system in which you can customize operating environments and applications on-demand. As compared to Windows, Linux Mint is a much more secure platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 things to do in Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-things-to-do-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-things-to-do-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>10 Things To Do After Installing Linux Welcome to Linux! So you&amp;rsquo;ve found [a site][1], read some blog or other online article that tells you that switching to Linux is worthwhile and you&amp;rsquo;ve made the switch. So of course you&amp;rsquo;re now asking yourself &amp;ldquo;what are the next ten things that I should to do?&amp;rdquo; which is understandable because that&amp;rsquo;s what we all do when we start using something unfamiliar to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Linux with CHRX</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-linux-with-chrx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-linux-with-chrx/</guid>
      <description>Note: to do this, all your chromeOS data will be wiped. I recommend reading through all of this post before starting.
This post is about how I got my chromebook dual booting galliumOS.
Step one: go into Developer mode. Developer mode is a setting that lets you do development. It&amp;rsquo;s not on by default because it also makes it easier to install a malicious package. (APKs, or android packages, can&amp;rsquo;t be opened without developer mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-linux/</guid>
      <description>{: .box-warning} Warning: This will wipe all data from device
Getting an iso
-step 1: download an iso of the distro. some user friendly distros i recommend for beginners are ubuntu, and linux lite. once you get the iso file, it should be 1.0GB+
-step 2: Burn the iso to a disk or usb drive. i use a tool called etcher. download it at https://etcher.io once the iso is burned, put usb or disk in device and move on to your device instructions</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
