<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 22:40:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To Be or Not to Be</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/to-be-or-not-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 22:40:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/to-be-or-not-to-be/</guid>
      <description>To Be or Not to Be, That is the Question Sometimes, people will question their actions. Sometimes people have 2 different identities: the one they keep to themselves, and the one that they share with others. This personality, this way of life, is common in lots of people. When you think something to yourself, and say something else. When you have a secret that you know can not be told. To Be or Not To Be, That is the Question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of Good and Bad Leaders</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/traits-of-good-and-bad-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 17:37:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/traits-of-good-and-bad-leaders/</guid>
      <description>Traits of Good and Bad Leaders Successful businesses need leaders, someone who can inspire employees and lead them, and the business towards success. Leaders encourage others to work to their full potential, inspire creativity, and aid motivation. During turbulent economic times, the need for good leaders intensifies. Someone who presents a clear vision for recovery leads by example and instills confidence in those around them. A good leader has many traits, if you can recognize these within yourself and capitalize on them, then you may become a successful leader in your work environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Minecraft</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/the-secret-of-minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 08:40:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/the-secret-of-minecraft/</guid>
      <description>The secret of Minecraft And its challenge to the rest of us minecraft.gamepedia.com
It’s almost inevitable: I encounter *Minecraft *somewhere online—it’s easy to do, because there’s a lot of Minecraft out there—and I end up convinced I’m doing the wrong thing with my life.
Let me explain.
Briefly, for the uninitiated: Minecraft is a video game, first released in 2009 as a buggy prototype by a solo Swedish programmer named Markus Persson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plagiarism in Free software</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/plagiarism-in-free-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 08:24:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/plagiarism-in-free-software/</guid>
      <description>Plagiarism in Free Software Note: the opinions expressed here are solely mine. (Duh)
Something that I take rather seriously is the copying and redistibution without credit (intentionally or otherwise) of free software, i.e. plagiarism.
There&amp;rsquo;s a huge difference between something being in the public domain and being free and open source. The latter has a license, for one, and the purpose of it being under license is to preserve the rights of the author(s) to their work(s) but some people either misunderstand or ignore that distinction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
