<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shell on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shell on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 11:43:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disable Snaps in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 11:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Intro Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, snaps are great in theory - If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar, a snap package is like a sandboxed application that is packaged in such a way that:
 You can be sure you&amp;rsquo;re running exactly what the app developer intended, as all dependencies and assets are bundled into the snap application package The snap application generally doesn&amp;rsquo;t own your entire system, it runs in an application sandbox of sorts Snaps are cross-platform and distributed independently from apt/deb packages, and as such are usually more up to date than those found in apt  Now this all sounds great, and it is in some ways (especially for app developers), but it comes at a cost: and that is generally performance and annoyances with application theming, access to user folders, and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:05:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know From switching your private keys to directory listings with hidden files
As a developer, there are two key things that are paramount to a productive setup: speed and efficiency.
The more time you take to accomplish simple tasks like searching for files or displaying their contents, the more is taken from critical development time. When working on the command-line, things like aliases and custom functions can speed things up and let you get back to developing more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
