<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 21:28:35 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacobgoldstein.tk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Try Linux Online</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/try-linux-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 21:28:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/try-linux-online/</guid>
      <description>DistroTest is a web service that allows you to test Linux and Unix operating systems online for free, without having to install them locally. You can try 300+ Linux and Unix operating systems online without having to install them locally. Just visit the website, choose the Linux/Unix distro of your choice and run it!
The creators of DistroTest have hosted this web service on Debian using Qemu. There is no restrictions to use the distros listed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All MCU Movies Ranked</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/all-mcu-movies-ranked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:20:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/all-mcu-movies-ranked/</guid>
      <description>All Marvel Cinematic Universe Movies Ranked With ‘Avengers: Endgame’ in theaters, how do the 22 films of the MCU stack up?
Eleven years and twenty-two films. It’s crazy to think about. When you look back at some of the Marvel Cinematic Universe’s early work, they look rather quaint compared to the epic *Avengers: Endgame*. The first film of the series, Iron Man (2008), was released to theaters when I was fifteen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Avengers Messed Up Bad</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/the-avengers-messed-up-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 10:12:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/the-avengers-messed-up-bad/</guid>
      <description>The Avengers Messed Up The Avengers Messed Up
How our favorite superheroes ruined the world they meant to save © Marvel Studios
It’s no spoiler to reveal that in Avengers: Endgame, the good guys end up defeating the bad guys. That’s just how superhero stories work — at least in the second half of a two-part film series. But the Avengers don’t seem to realize that they’ve created many more problems in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The XY Files- the Lost Plot of Gen 6</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/the-xy-files-the-lost-plot-of-gen-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:07:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/the-xy-files-the-lost-plot-of-gen-6/</guid>
      <description>The XY Files: The Lost Plot of Pokemon’s 6th Generation Scrapped, Leaked, Posted and Forgotten
Game Freak and The Pokemon Company have always been very secretive. Alpha and Beta builds of their games are almost mythic in rarity, and we so rarely get to see early or scrapped Pokemon designs. Everything remains in the vault, even the garbage.
This secrecy has engendered a history of speculation regarding upcoming games and Pokemon designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Minecraft</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/the-secret-of-minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 08:40:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/the-secret-of-minecraft/</guid>
      <description>The secret of Minecraft And its challenge to the rest of us minecraft.gamepedia.com
It’s almost inevitable: I encounter *Minecraft *somewhere online—it’s easy to do, because there’s a lot of Minecraft out there—and I end up convinced I’m doing the wrong thing with my life.
Let me explain.
Briefly, for the uninitiated: Minecraft is a video game, first released in 2009 as a buggy prototype by a solo Swedish programmer named Markus Persson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Ricing Basics</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/linux-ricing-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 17:43:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/linux-ricing-basics/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Here are my dotfiles.
Disclaimer: I am in no way a ricing expert. This guide is intended for fellow beginners confused on the very basics when it comes to the customization of their Unix system.
Introduction After making my departure to Arch Linux a month ago I was quickly introduced to the world of tiling window managers. The idea is that instead of having a full blown desktop environment (DE) such as Gnome or Unity, you just have a window manager that utilizes keyboard shortcuts to organize your windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Snaps in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 11:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Intro Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, snaps are great in theory - If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar, a snap package is like a sandboxed application that is packaged in such a way that:
 You can be sure you&amp;rsquo;re running exactly what the app developer intended, as all dependencies and assets are bundled into the snap application package The snap application generally doesn&amp;rsquo;t own your entire system, it runs in an application sandbox of sorts Snaps are cross-platform and distributed independently from apt/deb packages, and as such are usually more up to date than those found in apt  Now this all sounds great, and it is in some ways (especially for app developers), but it comes at a cost: and that is generally performance and annoyances with application theming, access to user folders, and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entire Mcu Timeline Explained</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/entire-mcu-timeline-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 21:24:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/entire-mcu-timeline-explained/</guid>
      <description>With over 20 films and a handful of TV shows spread out over more than a decade, the Marvel Cinematic Universe is the biggest franchise in the pop culture landscape — and despite the fact that they called the most recent movie Endgame, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it&amp;rsquo;s going to be stopping any time soon. That massive scope has allowed Marvel Studios to create a sprawling, interconnected universe built on a shared continuity, and much like the comics the MCU is based on, that means things can get pretty complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Learn Linux</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/why-you-should-learn-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:50:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/why-you-should-learn-linux/</guid>
      <description>Why You Should Probably Learn Linux Let’s face it, Linux sounds scary to the untrained ear. Most average users think of black and white terminals, and pale, white, basement dwellers clacking assembly and basic into an ancient IBM machine when they hear the term “ Linux” arise in conversation. Of course, the same might not be said for Data Scientists, and programmers alike, but the stigma is certainly still illustrated inside of that particular clique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:05:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know From switching your private keys to directory listings with hidden files
As a developer, there are two key things that are paramount to a productive setup: speed and efficiency.
The more time you take to accomplish simple tasks like searching for files or displaying their contents, the more is taken from critical development time. When working on the command-line, things like aliases and custom functions can speed things up and let you get back to developing more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
