<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 14:32:34 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Worst MCU Plotholes</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/worst-mcu-plotholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 14:32:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/worst-mcu-plotholes/</guid>
      <description>There is no denying that the Marvel Cinematic Universe, more commonly known as the MCU, has pretty much taken over the world. Since Iron Man first burst onto our screens back in 2008, the MCU has laid out a series of intricate movies and TV shows that have created not just an entertainment universe, but an entire entertainment experience and a new way to enjoy and experience movies.
Generally speaking, the MCU has prided itself on its continuity throughout its universe with each movie being a single, stand alone installment but also a small cog in a larger, overarching storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Min Browser Almost Good Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/min-browser-almost-good-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 19:42:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/min-browser-almost-good-enough/</guid>
      <description>Min Browser: Almost good enough The Min Browser is a minimalist web browser designed for productivity. In this review, I, Cukmekerb, will try it and tell you what I think.
First thoughts Min is not in the AUR (there&amp;rsquo;s a beta version that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated since 2018), but it it is available to download as a .deb or .rpm. Since I&amp;rsquo;m running Manjaro, which is not based on Debian, I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Debtap to install it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:17:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Brief: This tutorial shows you how to install Arch Linux in easy to follow steps.
Arch Linux is a general-purpose rolling release Linux distribution which is very popular among the DIY enthusiasts and hardcore Linux users.
The default installation covers only a minimal base system and expects the end user to configure the system by himself/herself.
This is why installing Arch Linux is a challenge in itself but at the same time, it is a learning opportunity for intermediate Linux users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Markdown in Vim</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-markdown-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 09:05:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-markdown-in-vim/</guid>
      <description>If you are working with something that works like CommonMark and does not insert a &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; for every newline character then you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to display trailing spaces, so that you know when you actually have the two trailing spaces needed to insert a &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;. See Showing Invisible Things In Vim for how to do this.
Troubleshooting In the course of writing this I encountered a number of problems.
Terminal Vim displayed a background color for italic text and bold text was bolded, but in my Gui Vim they both just looked like all the other text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Programming Jokes</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/simple-programming-jokes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:30:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/simple-programming-jokes/</guid>
      <description>Life of a Programmer in Simple Jokes That Will Make You Laugh You don’t have to be a programmer to laugh at their humor.
Credit: gfycat.com
Programmers code all day, debug all night and go through thousands of code lines. But it doesn’t mean programming is what they all know and good at.
They all have a sense of humor that can make us all laugh even if we’re not a programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your Productivity With Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/boost-your-productivity-with-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 18:26:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/boost-your-productivity-with-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Boost your productivity using Markdown. What’s Markdown?
 Markdown is a lightweight markup language with plain text formatting syntax. It is designed so that it can be converted to HTML and many other formats using a tool by the same name. from Wikipedia
 Introducing the markdown formatting ⛷
1. Heading # h1 ## h2 ### h3 standard  2. Emphasis *Italic type* **Bold** ~~Negative~~  3. Fold Fold the long sentences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orion Twitch Client for Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/orion-twitch-client-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:57:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/orion-twitch-client-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>Orion- Twitch Client For Linux Orion is a free and open source QML / C++ client for Twitch.tv which can use multiple player backends (including mpv). The application runs on Linux, Windows, macOS and Android. Using Orion you can watch live Twitch streams and past broadcasts, and browse or search games and channels using a nice material user interface. What&amp;rsquo;s more, Orion lets you login to Twitch, so you can chat and follow channels (and receive notifications when a channel you follow goes online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Still Use Vim</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-i-still-use-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:37:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-i-still-use-vim/</guid>
      <description>Why I Still Use Vim And no, it’s not because I can’t figure out how to close it.
Image: http://amzn.to/2umsBaY
I often get asked about why I use Vim as my primary editor, there is no particular reason for this, except that I ended up learning it when I moved over to Linux full time many years ago. I ended up liking it because I could edit my small source files on my quad-core machine without needing to wait forever for the file to open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Galliumos on Chromebook</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/how-to-install-galliumos-on-chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 23:12:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/how-to-install-galliumos-on-chromebook/</guid>
      <description>— May 24, 2020
This is a repost of a guide I made on a different blogging platform when I only owned an ex-chromebook. It talks about how to install unlocked BIOS and install GalliumOS (a linux distro using xfce to make a chromeOS - like linux experience.)) Note: to do this, all your chromeOS data will be wiped. I recommend reading through all of this post before starting.
This post is about how I got my chromebook dual booting galliumOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Essential Vim Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-essential-vim-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 16:25:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-essential-vim-plugins/</guid>
      <description>10 essential Vim plugins Vim remains a powerful and ubiquitous application to tackle any number of text editing tasks conveniently from the terminal (some learning required). If you’re looking to add Vim to your toolkit this year, here is my list of absolutely essential plugins to begin supercharging your workflow.
If you’ve never set up a Vim plugin before, see the Installing Vim plugins section later on for a runthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
