<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MCU on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/mcu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MCU on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 14:32:34 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/mcu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Worst MCU Plotholes</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/worst-mcu-plotholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 14:32:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/worst-mcu-plotholes/</guid>
      <description>There is no denying that the Marvel Cinematic Universe, more commonly known as the MCU, has pretty much taken over the world. Since Iron Man first burst onto our screens back in 2008, the MCU has laid out a series of intricate movies and TV shows that have created not just an entertainment universe, but an entire entertainment experience and a new way to enjoy and experience movies.
Generally speaking, the MCU has prided itself on its continuity throughout its universe with each movie being a single, stand alone installment but also a small cog in a larger, overarching storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All MCU Movies Ranked</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/all-mcu-movies-ranked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:20:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/all-mcu-movies-ranked/</guid>
      <description>All Marvel Cinematic Universe Movies Ranked With ‘Avengers: Endgame’ in theaters, how do the 22 films of the MCU stack up?
Eleven years and twenty-two films. It’s crazy to think about. When you look back at some of the Marvel Cinematic Universe’s early work, they look rather quaint compared to the epic *Avengers: Endgame*. The first film of the series, Iron Man (2008), was released to theaters when I was fifteen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Avengers Messed Up Bad</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/the-avengers-messed-up-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 10:12:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/the-avengers-messed-up-bad/</guid>
      <description>The Avengers Messed Up The Avengers Messed Up
How our favorite superheroes ruined the world they meant to save © Marvel Studios
It’s no spoiler to reveal that in Avengers: Endgame, the good guys end up defeating the bad guys. That’s just how superhero stories work — at least in the second half of a two-part film series. But the Avengers don’t seem to realize that they’ve created many more problems in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entire Mcu Timeline Explained</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/entire-mcu-timeline-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 21:24:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/entire-mcu-timeline-explained/</guid>
      <description>With over 20 films and a handful of TV shows spread out over more than a decade, the Marvel Cinematic Universe is the biggest franchise in the pop culture landscape — and despite the fact that they called the most recent movie Endgame, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it&amp;rsquo;s going to be stopping any time soon. That massive scope has allowed Marvel Studios to create a sprawling, interconnected universe built on a shared continuity, and much like the comics the MCU is based on, that means things can get pretty complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
