<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:17:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:17:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/install-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Brief: This tutorial shows you how to install Arch Linux in easy to follow steps.
Arch Linux is a general-purpose rolling release Linux distribution which is very popular among the DIY enthusiasts and hardcore Linux users.
The default installation covers only a minimal base system and expects the end user to configure the system by himself/herself.
This is why installing Arch Linux is a challenge in itself but at the same time, it is a learning opportunity for intermediate Linux users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Markdown in Vim</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-markdown-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 09:05:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/using-markdown-in-vim/</guid>
      <description>If you are working with something that works like CommonMark and does not insert a &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; for every newline character then you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to display trailing spaces, so that you know when you actually have the two trailing spaces needed to insert a &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;. See Showing Invisible Things In Vim for how to do this.
Troubleshooting In the course of writing this I encountered a number of problems.
Terminal Vim displayed a background color for italic text and bold text was bolded, but in my Gui Vim they both just looked like all the other text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orion Twitch Client for Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/orion-twitch-client-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:57:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/orion-twitch-client-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>Orion- Twitch Client For Linux Orion is a free and open source QML / C++ client for Twitch.tv which can use multiple player backends (including mpv). The application runs on Linux, Windows, macOS and Android. Using Orion you can watch live Twitch streams and past broadcasts, and browse or search games and channels using a nice material user interface. What&amp;rsquo;s more, Orion lets you login to Twitch, so you can chat and follow channels (and receive notifications when a channel you follow goes online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Still Use Vim</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-i-still-use-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:37:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/why-i-still-use-vim/</guid>
      <description>Why I Still Use Vim And no, it’s not because I can’t figure out how to close it.
Image: http://amzn.to/2umsBaY
I often get asked about why I use Vim as my primary editor, there is no particular reason for this, except that I ended up learning it when I moved over to Linux full time many years ago. I ended up liking it because I could edit my small source files on my quad-core machine without needing to wait forever for the file to open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Galliumos on Chromebook</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/how-to-install-galliumos-on-chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 23:12:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/how-to-install-galliumos-on-chromebook/</guid>
      <description>— May 24, 2020
This is a repost of a guide I made on a different blogging platform when I only owned an ex-chromebook. It talks about how to install unlocked BIOS and install GalliumOS (a linux distro using xfce to make a chromeOS - like linux experience.)) Note: to do this, all your chromeOS data will be wiped. I recommend reading through all of this post before starting.
This post is about how I got my chromebook dual booting galliumOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Essential Vim Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-essential-vim-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 16:25:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/10-essential-vim-plugins/</guid>
      <description>10 essential Vim plugins Vim remains a powerful and ubiquitous application to tackle any number of text editing tasks conveniently from the terminal (some learning required). If you’re looking to add Vim to your toolkit this year, here is my list of absolutely essential plugins to begin supercharging your workflow.
If you’ve never set up a Vim plugin before, see the Installing Vim plugins section later on for a runthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Reasons Why Linux Is Better</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/12-reasons-why-linux-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 21:44:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/12-reasons-why-linux-is-better/</guid>
      <description>12 reasons why Linux is better than Windows The myth that Linux is complex and only needed by programmers and developers is not true.
Windows is the most popular operating system, and it is well deserved. She has come a long way, constantly improving and developing. However, although Microsoft claims that the Ten is its best creation, in some things Linux is far superior to Windows.
1. Convenient implementation of updates Perhaps we all know about this situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fascinating Arch Linux Rice</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/the-fascinating-arch-linux-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 16:45:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/the-fascinating-arch-linux-rice/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I dive into Linux the third time. The first time is in my childhood, I was attracted by the magazines, which introduced me the hacker culture. The second time was weird, I wanted to focus on study instead of PC gaming.
This time, it&amp;rsquo;s totally different. /r/unixporn and /r/MechanicalKeyboards attracted me. The most fascinating part of that is RICE or RICE culture.
RICE RICE is not the food rice. Instead, it is the acronym of Race Inspired Cosmetic Enhancements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Ricing and How I Do It (just the basics)</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-ricing-and-how-i-do-it-just-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 13:15:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/linux-ricing-and-how-i-do-it-just-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>Everyone is always asking me, how do I rice linux so fast? And The answer is, I just have the some bash scripts set to keybinds. For the i3 window manager.
Script 1: Pywal So for this one you need pywal.
wal -i $HOME/Pictures/wallpapers -o wal-set Script 2: Sublime text theme This is a python script
#! /usr/bin/env python import json import os def make_element(name, scope, **kwargs): &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;Helper function for generating color scheme entries&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; result = {} result[&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;] = name result[&amp;#39;scope&amp;#39;] = scope result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life So Far</title>
      <link>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/my-life-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacobgoldstein.tk/posts/my-life-so-far/</guid>
      <description>My Life So Far So, I had an idea to just write about my life today, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m gonna do. Enjoy!
Projects I am working on  Opensuspect (more on this later) AlamodeBoot My website  Things I have done  CFWed my 3ds installed i3 and made it look cool got 1.4k upvotes on reddit  Things I want to do  Install Arch Linux Format my stupid corrupted SD card make more storage on my laptop  Opensuspect So, OpenSuspect is an open-source social deduction game, similar to among us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
