<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Jacob Goldstein&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 17:43:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacobgoldstein.tk/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Ricing Basics</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/linux-ricing-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 17:43:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/linux-ricing-basics/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Here are my dotfiles.
Disclaimer: I am in no way a ricing expert. This guide is intended for fellow beginners confused on the very basics when it comes to the customization of their Unix system.
Introduction After making my departure to Arch Linux a month ago I was quickly introduced to the world of tiling window managers. The idea is that instead of having a full blown desktop environment (DE) such as Gnome or Unity, you just have a window manager that utilizes keyboard shortcuts to organize your windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Snaps in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 11:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/disable-snaps-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Intro Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, snaps are great in theory - If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar, a snap package is like a sandboxed application that is packaged in such a way that:
 You can be sure you&amp;rsquo;re running exactly what the app developer intended, as all dependencies and assets are bundled into the snap application package The snap application generally doesn&amp;rsquo;t own your entire system, it runs in an application sandbox of sorts Snaps are cross-platform and distributed independently from apt/deb packages, and as such are usually more up to date than those found in apt  Now this all sounds great, and it is in some ways (especially for app developers), but it comes at a cost: and that is generally performance and annoyances with application theming, access to user folders, and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Learn Linux</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/why-you-should-learn-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:50:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/why-you-should-learn-linux/</guid>
      <description>Why You Should Probably Learn Linux Let’s face it, Linux sounds scary to the untrained ear. Most average users think of black and white terminals, and pale, white, basement dwellers clacking assembly and basic into an ancient IBM machine when they hear the term “ Linux” arise in conversation. Of course, the same might not be said for Data Scientists, and programmers alike, but the stigma is certainly still illustrated inside of that particular clique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:05:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/6-terminal-commands-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>6 Terminal Commands You Should Know From switching your private keys to directory listings with hidden files
As a developer, there are two key things that are paramount to a productive setup: speed and efficiency.
The more time you take to accomplish simple tasks like searching for files or displaying their contents, the more is taken from critical development time. When working on the command-line, things like aliases and custom functions can speed things up and let you get back to developing more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Linux Software</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/best-linux-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:02:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/best-linux-software/</guid>
      <description>Best Linux Desktop Software Awards per Category for 2017! hey! you do realize that this post is only written because i was bored to do anything else, right?
also i want to make super clear that on these awards, we ran a set of completely democratic procedures, with a fully transparent voting. and by “we” i mean “me”, and by “voting” i mean a single vote! “mine” 👐
i will try to cover some basic categories, but not everything!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Survival Guide</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/linux-survival-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 13:02:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/linux-survival-guide/</guid>
      <description>Linux: A Survival Guide for Beginners I survived the transition to Linux—and you can too
Photo by Chris Ried on Unsplash
Switching from Windows to Linux can be really scary. But if you can survive the first few months, the eventual returns are exponential. Here’s how I survived.
TLDR   Though I am just an amateur in Linux, I was able to survive the transition and indeed benefitted from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ventoy Persistence</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/ventoy-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/ventoy-persistence/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I have discussed how to create multiboot USB drives with Ventoy application. Today, I will see how to create persistent bootable USB using Ventoy in Linux. As you may already know, a regular bootable medium allows us to test the Linux distributions without having to install them on the hard drive. When you are on a Live OS, you can do all sort of things, such as installing applications, downloading files, playing media, creating files and folders, customizing it as per your liking and a lot more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ventoy Multiboot USB</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/ventoy-multiboot-usb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/ventoy-multiboot-usb/</guid>
      <description>Ventoy is a free, open source and cross-platform program to create multiboot USB drives in Linux and MS Windows. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to format your USB devices over and over. Just create a bootable USB drive once and add as many as ISOs you want in future. Ventoy will automatically create the menu entries for the newly added ISOs and add them to the boot menu. Once you created the multiboot USB, boot your system with the USB drive, select the ISO you want to load and start using it in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Linux Commands</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/important-linux-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/important-linux-commands/</guid>
      <description>Important Linux Commands: Linux Commands You Must Know In 1991 when Linus Torvalds for the first time publicly shared his newly made kernel completely free from minix code, then even he was not aware of its capabilities in bringing the revolution in the software industry at that time. The open source we hear today was not much popular back then, not until linux was founded. You see, Git a very popular VCS(Version Control System) was founded by the same guy to maintain the linux kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/install-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobgoldstein.tk/install-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>After witnessing insane minimalism paired with a tiler (tiling window manager), knew it was my time to take the pilgrimage to Arch Linux. Some characteristics that make Arch unique:
 The Arch Way embody the principles behind Arch Linux; simplicity, modernity, pragmatism, user centrality and versatility. Forces one to build the system up by hand. This encourages you to question the role of each component of the system, and available options to satisfy that component (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
